Guide to the Morrison Gunn family letters, 1844-1869 MS 151
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Morrison Gunn family letters
1844-1869
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Berger, Samuel; Gunn, Wannay Fred; Gunn, Morrison; Gunn, Ann
MS 151
0.1 Linear Feet 49 photocopied letters in 1 folder
Photocopies of 49 letters to Morrison Gunn from members of his family and various friends. For the most part they are personal, but also include information on the conditions faced by immigrant farmers and the problems of establishing a home.
Biographical Note
Morrison Gunn was born in Edinburgh, Scotland circa 1820. He left Scotland for the United States as an adult  somewhere between the late 1830s and the early 1840s and first lived in Laurens, Otsego County, New York. Subsequent addresses include Cold Water and Ann Arbor, Michigan and Angola, Indiana. He was employed by the American Car Company of Chicago. He was a private in the 129th Regiment of Indiana Volunteers from November 23, 1863, until his discharge on July 10, 1865 in Greensboro, North Carolina.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of photocopies of 49 letters to Morrison Gunn from members of his family and various friends. For the most part they are personal, but also include information on the conditions faced by immigrant farmers and the problems of establishing a home.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Photocopies donated by Mr. Dale A. Letts in September 1963. Orignals now held by Sarah L. Atherton, Mr. Letts daughter.
Index Terms
Subjects
Agriculture; Emigration and immigration; Social life and customs
Document Types
corrrespondence
Places
United States
- Series I: Letters, 1844-1849, 11547
  - Wannay Fred Gunn to unknown (Esteemed Friends), April 3, 1844, 11564 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Morreson Gunn, June 1, 1845, 11563 (Folder 1)
  - Moreson Gunn to Moreson(?), June 2, 1845, 11562 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to father (Morrison Gunn), September 28, 1845, 11561 (Folder 1)
  - Daniel E. Palmer to unknown, December 18, 1845, 11560 (Folder 1)
  - Robert Gunn to Morrison Gunn, May 23, 1846, 11559 (Folder 1)
  - John and Margaret Ryan to brother (Morrison Gunn), July 15, 1846, 11558 (Folder 1)
  - John Ryan to Morrison Gunn, July 20, 1847, 11557 (Folder 1)
  - B Sture(?) to Morrison Gunn, July 27, 1847, 11556 (Folder 1)
  - Wannay Fred Gunn to Morrison Gunn, November 21, 1847, 11555 (Folder 1)
  - B Sture(?) to Morrison Gunn, January 24, 1848, 11554 (Folder 1)
  - John R. Massun to Morrison Gunn, January 25, 1848, 11553 (Folder 1)
  - William Comstock to Morrison Gunn, February 29, 1848, 11552 (Folder 1)
  - John and Margaret Ryan to Morrison Gunn; & unknown to Morrison Gunn, December 18, 1848, 11551 (Folder 1)
  - Son of Morrison Gunn to Morrison Gunn, January 20, 1849, 11550 (Folder 1)
  - Ann Gunn to Morrison Gunn, Febuary 23, 1849, 11549 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Morrison Gunn, March 20, 1848 or 1849, 11548 (Folder 1)
- Series II: Letters, 1850-1859, 11529
  - Morrison Gunn to unknown, January 19, 1850; & John Ryan to Morrison Gunn, October 10, 1850, 11546 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Morrison Gunn, July 6, 1850, 11545 (Folder 1)
  - Addison P. Strong to Friends Gunn & Ryan, September 26, 1850, 11544 (Folder 1)
  - American Car Co. to Morrison Gunn, February 22, 1854, 11543 (Folder 1)
  - Ann Berger (daughter of Morrison Gunn) to Morrison Gunn, June 17, 1854, 11542 (Folder 1)
  - James Gunn to Morrison Gunn, July 15, 1854, 11541 (Folder 1)
  - Samuel Berger to Morrison Gunn, July 15, 1954, 11540 (Folder 1)
  - Samuel Berger to Morrison Gunn, August 11, 1854, 11539 (Folder 1)
  - Samuel Berger to Morrison Gunn, October 8, 1854, 11538 (Folder 1)
  - Samuel Berger to Morrison Gunn, October 30, 1854, 11537 (Folder 1)
  - Ann Berger to Morrison Gunn, November 27, 1854, 11536 (Folder 1)
  - Samuel Berger to Morrison Gunn, December 18, 1854, 11535 (Folder 1)
  - Morrison Gunn to James Jackson (monetary transfer), February 3, 1954; & Morrison Gunn to unknown (monetary transfer), May 1 1855, 11534 (Folder 1)
  - Samuel Berger to Morrison Gunn, February 19, 1855, 11533 (Folder 1)
  - Thomas English to Morrison Gunn, September 8,1855, 11532 (Folder 1)
  - Thomas English to Morrison Gunn, February 14, 1856, 11531 (Folder 1)
  - Morrison Gunn to unknown (monetary transfer), May 7, 1859, 11530 (Folder 1)
- Series III: Letters, 1860-1869, 11517
  - Unknown to Morrison Gunn (bill), September 5, 1860; & William Barkhuff to Morrison Gunn, October 27, 1855, 11528 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to unknown, April 26, 1862, 11527 (Folder 1)
  - Cornelia Allen & David Butler to sister (unknown), December 1, 1862, 11526 (Folder 1)
  - John Armstrong to Morrison Gunn, December 11, 1862, 11525 (Folder 1)
  - David Allen and Cornelia Allen to sister (unknown), January 15, 1863, 11524 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to unknown, March 5, 1863, 11523 (Folder 1)
  - David Allen & Cornelia Allen to sister (unknown), May 4, 1863, 11522 (Folder 1)
  - Moore, to cousin (unknown), May 15, 1863, 11521 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Nelson(?), August 8, 1863, 11520 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Morrison Gunn (discharge from army), July 18, 1865, 11519 (Folder 1)
  - Morrison Gunn to unknown (monetary transfer), April 8, 1869, 11518 (Folder 1)
- Series IV: Undated letters, 11513
  - Unknown to Morrison Gunn (envelope), February 20? (no year given), 11516 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Morrison Gunn (envelope), September 29? (no year given), 11515 (Folder 1)
  - John Ryan to Morrison Gunn, September 30? (no year given), 11514 (Folder 1)